As someone with an AI background,
I think you can probably explain to us,
you know, this whole hype of generative AI, right?
I mean, right now people want generative AI in everything.
What is this about? Right?
I mean, what is the potential that's been unlocked with
the GPT-3 and so on? Can you help us understand
from a lay person's perspective, right?
What this has done and what the future holds? Sure.
So I think if we just take a step back
and think about all the creative things as
humans do, you know, basically it's
like we collect from five senses that
we have and we output. That output could
be speech or written stuff
or art, etc. And just
think about generative AI the same thing,
which is an AI comes in the place of the human
and it generates what a human can generate,
which is speech or text
or images or videos, things
like that, etc. And what happened
and the biggest transformative thing that
happened in the last one, two,
two years, three years span is the
AI generation catching up with human levels.
I mean, if you take just three years back,
you would know what is AI written content.
You would know what is AI generated image.
Now the line between AI generated
and human creativity generated has blurred
and that has been blurred only in the last one year most
actively, whether these Stable diffusion, Dalle
models,  I mean, text to image models
or chat GPT, which responds
to almost like a human like conversation
and all these modalities, when I mean modalities,
text, image, speech and
the human sensory experience that we have!
Right now, AI is able to replicate one human sensory
experience, whether you are able to draw a nice illustration,
AI can do that. Whether you are able to
write a story, AI can do that. But think about
what real humans do! In the sense that
let us say if you write a story,
you can illustrate the story with specific
characters and even if you have 100 illustrations,
those characters and their attributes
flow through the 100 images that you
have throughout the story or book
and there is a coherence, there is a coherence between
text, images and
if you narrate that yourself with your voice,
there is a coherence on how you stress on important
characters, how you stress on other things.
So right now, AI is doing one task very well,
But let us think about generative AI
evolving into a multimodal generative AI,
those text and the illustrations that
accompany with them will be in coherence that is
there is continuity between images,
the same character is going to other place, etc things like that.
So what we can foresee in the future is multimodal AI,
doing more multimodal, multi-sensory generative AI
tasks that humans do.